And that's the match
比赛到此为止
Lucky shot
你运气好而已
Well done, Miss Nikos
干得漂亮，Nikos小姐
You should have no problem qualifying for the tournament
你获取锦标赛的参赛资格应该没问题
Thank you, professor
谢谢你，教授
Alright
很好
Now I know that's a tough act to follow, but we have time for one more sparring match
我知道要跟上这种水平不容易，但我们还有时间再来一场对战
Any volunteers?
有自愿的吗？
Ms. Belladonna?
Belladonna小姐？
You've been rather docile for the past few classes
最近几堂课你安分得有点阿卡林啊
Why don't you..
要不你..
I'll do it
让我上
Mercury, is it?
你叫Mercury，是吧？
Very well
很好
Let's find you an opponent
我给你找个对手
Actually
其实
I wanna fight..her
我想跟..她打
Me?
我？
I'm afraid Miss Nikos has just finished the match
真遗憾，Nikos小姐刚打完比赛
I recommend you choose another partner
我建议你换一个对手
No! it's fine
没，挺好的
I'd be happy to oblige
我乐意效劳
Hey, your friend's doing pretty good
嘿，你朋友打得挺好嘛
Humm..
哼..
I forfeit
我弃权
You..
你..
..don't even want to try?
..都不想试着打赢？
What's the point?
意义何在？
You're a world-renowned fighter, we're obviously leagues apart
你是举世闻名的战士，我们明显差太远
In that case..
既然如此..
Pyrrha Nikos is the victor of the match..again
Pyrrha Nikos 再次获得了比赛胜利
Next time you may want to think a little harder before choosing an opponent
下次挑对手前还是多仔细考虑考虑
I'll be sure to do that
我一定考虑
That is all for today
今天就到这里
And remember, the dance is this weekend
还要记住，舞会在这个周末
But you all have your first mission on Monday
但你们周一都有首项任务
I will not accept any excuses
我不接受任何缺席的理由
Learning is so much fun
学习真是愉♂快啊
Hey, Blake!
嘿，Blake！
You uh..doing okay?
你..还好吧？
I'm fine
我没事
So I hear there's this dance going on this weekend..
我听说这周末有个舞会..
and sounds pretty lame, but..
听起来很烂，但..
you and me, I'm thinking, not as lame, huh?
你我一起去，我觉得就不烂了吧？
What?
哈？
The dance! This weekend! You wanna go, or what?
舞会啊！这周末的，你想不想去？
I don't have time for a stupid dance
我可没空去个逗比舞会
I thought you of all people would get that
我以为所有人里你最清楚
You what?
你们说啥？
We want you to go to the dance
我们希望你去参加舞会
That's ridiculous
真是荒谬
Blake, we're worried about you
Blake，我们很担心你
This investigation is starting to mess with your head
这调查已经开始让你脑子糊涂了
You can't sleep, you hardly eat
你睡不着觉，几乎不吃饭
And to be honest, your grades have been suffering
说实话，你的成绩都变糟了
You think I care about grades? People's lives are at stake!
你认为我在乎成绩？人们的生命危在旦夕
We know, and we're also trying to figure out what Torchwick is up to
懂，我们也在想办法弄清Torchwick的阴谋
Thanks to you and Sun, we know they're operating somewhere outside of southeast Vale
托你和Sun的福，我们知道了他们在溪谷东南边某处有行动
And, the Schnee company records singled out Vale as the primary target for Dust robberies over the last few months
而且，雪倪公司的记录表明溪谷是这几个月发生尘晶抢劫案的主要地区
Don't forget about their missing military tech too
也别忘了他们失踪的军用机甲
But there're still unanswered questions!
但还有一些未解之谜！
Blake, you won't be able to find anything if you can't even keep your eyes open
Blake你如果连眼睛都睁不开，是根本无法调查的
All we're asking is that you take it easy for one day
我们只要你放松一天就好
It will be fun! Yang and I will make sure of it
会很有趣的！我和Yang可以保证
Yeah! We're planning the whole event!
对！我们在策划整个活动！
Excuse me?
你说什么？
Team CFVY's away mission lasted longer than expected
CFVY队的校外任务时间比预定要长
So, Weiss and I were asked to pick up where they left off
Weiss和我就被叫去接手他们剩下的活
And now we can make sure you have the perfect night
所以我们保证让你度过一个完美的夜晚
And once it's all over, we'll return to our search, rested and ready
当全部结束后，我们带着饱满的精神继续调查
So..what do you think?
所以..你觉得如何？
I think this is a colossal waste of time
我觉得这简直是挥霍光阴
I'll be in the library
我去图书馆了
Great
这下好了
She can't keep going like this
她不能再这么下去了
Weiss~
Weiss~
Oh, come on
唉，别闹
Open the door..
快开门呀..
I promise not to sing
我保证不唱了
I lied!
逗你呢！
Weiss Schnee
Weiss Schnee
Will you accompany me
愿与我一起
to the dance on..
去舞会吗..
Sunday
周日
Are you done?
唱完了？
Yes
是啊
No
没门
What?!
干嘛！？
And that is why they call you the Ice Queen
这就是为什么他们叫你冰雪女王
All my life, boys have only cared about the perks of my last name
活到现在遇见的男生都只在乎雪倪家族的福利
Besides
再说了
I already have a date in mind
我心里已经有舞伴人选了
Date or no date
不管有没有
None of this will matter if we can't get Blake to go
如果说服不了Blake参加，就都没意义
Well done!
干得好！
Your swordplay's improved immensely
你的剑术长进了很多啊
Couldn't have done it without you
没你在长进不了
So
那么
Are you ready to move on to Aura?
准备好修炼元气了么？
I'm actually thinking maybe we just skip Aura tonight?
我在想要不今晚就跳过元气这环吧？
Might go on a jog or something
可以去慢跑什么的
Come on
别呀
I know you get frustrated
我知道你很灰心
But you must keep trying
但你必须不断尝试
I'm sure we'll discover your Semblance any day now
我相信很快就能找出你潜在的外像力了
That's..not it
不是..那个问题
It's just..
我只是..
It's dumb
太二了
What is it?
你又咋了？
Jaune, you know you can tell me
Jaune，你完全可以告诉我
It's..Weiss
是..Weiss
Oh..
我去..
What about her?
她怎么了？
I asked her to the dance and she shot me down
我邀她做舞伴，她十分感动然后拒绝了我
Big surprise, right?
真没想到，哈？
Well
嘛
I believe the saying goes: There's..
我觉得俗话说得好：天涯..
plenty of fish in the sea
何处无芳草
That's easy for you to say
你说起来当然轻松
You've probably got guys clamoring over each other just to ask you out
那些想约你出去的家伙们都要吵翻天了吧
You'd be surprised
你猜错了
Oh please. If you don't get a date to the dance, I'll wear a dress
得了吧，要是你都找不到舞伴，我就穿裙子
Heh
呵呵
And finally, Pyrrha Nikos
然后终于是，Pyrrha Nikos
Ah, the invincible girl
啊，无敌的妹纸
She's smart
她很精明
But I wouldn't say invincible
但我不觉得无敌
Do tell
说说看
Her semblance is Polarity
她的外像力是 [极性操控]
But you'd never know just by watching
但只靠看是看不出来的
After she made contact with my boots, she was able to move them around however she wanted
她碰过我的靴子后，就能随心所欲地移动它们
But she only made slight adjustments
但她只做了微小的位移调整
Just enough to make it look like she's untouchable
正好让她看上去无法被攻击到
She doesn't broadcast her power, so it puts her opponent at a disadvantage
她从不明显地展示自己的能力，从而让对手处于劣势
People assume she's fated for victory
人们以为她命中注定是胜者
When she's really taking fate into her own hands
而她却用自己的双手掌控命运
Interesting
有意思
Add her to the list
把她加进名单
You should be able to take her no problem
你对付她应该没问题
It's not about overpowering the enemy
这不是为了打倒敌人
It's about taking away what power they have
而是为了夺走他们的力量
And we will, in time
迟早会办到的
I hate waiting!
我讨厌傻等！
Don't worry, Mercury
别担心，Mercury
We have a fun weekend ahead of us
有个愉快的周末在前面等着呢
BRB
BRB
This SUB is presented by Baidu RWBY Bar Creator: sbz_kid
本字幕由百度RWBY吧提供 片源/翻译/时间轴/特效/后期：sbz_kid